<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Kijani BlogA Grassroots Organization with a Difference &#8211; Kijani Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/2015/05/18/a-grassroots-organization-with-a-difference/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Kijani</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 08:39:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.18</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">81697008</site>	<item>
		<title>A Grassroots Organization with a Difference</title>
		<link>/2015/05/18/a-grassroots-organization-with-a-difference/</link>
		<comments>/2015/05/18/a-grassroots-organization-with-a-difference/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 13:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Oyaga]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youth]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.kijani.co/?p=382</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We are young people from around the world coming together to find shared solutions to the sustainability crisis. Learn about the power in our peculiarity. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Kijani team consists of college and Masters graduates and students with varying expertise. We’re wrapping our heads around the topic of sustainable forest rehabilitation, using our multiple skills to tackle various aspects of the project – from community engagement, website design and business modeling. This amalgamation of diverse cultures, skill-sets and perspectives in the team makes us unique, but working primarily in the Kenyan context – it is also easy to be viewed as inexperienced.</p>
<p>The truth is, an organization (an NGO for that matter) consisting entirely of youth, is somewhat of an anomaly in Kenya. In this culture, young people have to “earn” the respect of the “elderly” – it does not come automatically. There is an implicit dissimilarity of treatment between the demographic groups of the youth, and those who have jumped the proverbial fence into “adulthood”. Don’t get me wrong, we are adults, but that word has a bit of a nuanced definition in this part of the world.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/2014-12-05-A-Research-Grant-and-Dedication-to-a-Landscape-564x317.jpg" alt="Members of the Kijani team in the field in Marmanet" /></p>
<p>Last year in September, members of the Kijani team visited a certain office in the field, our main aim was to gather ecological information for our project. From the reception to the main office we were not treated fairly. After we left that office we went back to our offices in Nairobi where we analyzed our visit, conducting a small debrief about our meeting. It was shocking that our debrief revealed that the nature to which we were treated was due to the notion that we were youth; a pretext for inexperience.</p>
<p>Although it is true that we are young, the flip-side is that we are unique, dynamic and peculiar. We represent different fields of study, as well as different backgrounds and experiences. We are from different cultures and races. We represent a united world, working on shared solutions to the crises of the future; working on shared solutions to the crises of <em>our own</em> future.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Team_member-e1434632221345-564x366.jpg" alt="Members of the Kijani team saying a prayer before sharing a meal together" /></p>
<p>I believe in our uniqueness. When other organizations are dishing out handouts to enhance community participation, we advocate for voluntary participation so that community members can solve their own problems. When other organizations think of capacity building through workshops in communities, Kijani is thinking about walking together and building relationships with community members. When other organizations are thinking of imposing ideas to the communities in which they work, Kijani is building its foundation on the already local available knowledge.</p>
<p>These are the factors which make our organization stand out.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Prayer-e1434632985469-564x297.jpg" alt="Liz Wasirimba and Frithjof Gressmann are Kijani volunteers" /></p>
<p>We are willing to bring change and we are determined to do so. My point here is that regardless of people’s perception about you, whether negative or positive, you have the final say about who you are. This is our motivation as an organization. Since we are unique we are peculiar, and what makes us peculiar motivates us to achieve the goals that we have set for ourselves, for Kenya, and for the sustainable future of this planet.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	

		<wfw:commentRss>/2015/05/18/a-grassroots-organization-with-a-difference/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>

                            <media:content
                xmlns:media="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                url="http://kijani.co/imagerenderer/img.php?imgurl=http%3A%2F%2Fblog.kijani.ngo%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2015%2F05%2FTeam_member-e1434632221345-1600x900.jpg&amp;title=A+Grassroots+Organization+with+a+Difference&amp;width=600&amp;type=jpg&amp;qual=80"
              type="image/jpg"
              medium="image"
              height="337.5"
              width="600"
            />

	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">382</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
