<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Kijani BlogWhat does “Tree” mean to you? &#8211; Kijani Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/2015/02/15/what-does-tree-mean-to-you/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Kijani</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 08:39:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.18</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">81697008</site>	<item>
		<title>What does “Tree” mean to you?</title>
		<link>/2015/02/15/what-does-tree-mean-to-you/</link>
		<comments>/2015/02/15/what-does-tree-mean-to-you/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 14:16:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Haron Mambe]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reforestation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tree planting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.kijani.co/?p=263</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is a blog that invites consideration of the importance of trees for humans, habitats and the planet.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When you think of a tree, what resonates within your being? Just stop and think about it for a second&#8230; is it simply a giganteus plant that provides shade. For others, it may just act as a resource to provide a quick income. Well, to some degree this holds truth but a tree should mean much more that. When I think “tree”, this is what strikes me:</p>
<h2>T: Transformation</h2>
<p>How does a tree bring about transformation? Look at it this way, wherever there have been large expanses of land that have been deforested, it results in decreased water tables within the ground, degraded soil quality, likelihood of desertification, reduced biodiversity, just to name a few. This is negative transformation. With every tree that you plant and nurture, the transformation is greatly positive. A tree protects the soil, absorbs carbon and gives off water. A tree can help to contribute to harmony between people and the environment.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Young-loquat-300x169.jpg" alt="The sapling of a loquat tree - a kind of fruit tree" /></p>
<h2>R: Restoration</h2>
<p>Every single tree has the potential to restore the vital eco-systems so intertwined with the health of communities. Just imagine how much potential a whole forest of trees has! Reforestation and actual care and protection of trees can help to restore the environment from the negative effects of deforestation, contributing to the sustainable future of generations to come. The restorative effect of trees is evident in the fact that they are grown from a simple seed, they are a gift from nature unto nature – our role is simply to nurture the seed.</p>
<h2>E: Ecological Balance</h2>
<p>Ecology deals with the relations of organisms to one another and to their physical surroundings. Trees are tied to the capability of our planet of maintaining its own balance by providing vital services for a whole assortment of organisms – from the birds of the air to the fish in the rivers. I believe trees affect how all organisms relate. On one hand, man can stand to protect the trees. On the other hand, man might act out of greed and exploit the environment, valuing the gain from senseless destruction above his community.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/5-300x168.jpg" alt="Thompson Falls in Nyahururu, Kenya" /></p>
<h2>E: Earth</h2>
<p>Lastly, every tree that we do away with in an unsustainable way leads to the failing health of the earth. Think about it this way, if cells within our bodies were to begin dying one by one, eventually our health will be so affected leading to death. Every tree within our planet should be regarded as a cell. If the circumstances are right, then similar to a cell dividing itself and growing in number, then trees just as well will multiply, thus securing the earth’s health. Trees are pillars of stability and health in a world in constant flux.</p>
<p>Without trees, we compromise our future on this planet.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll leave you with this quote from the late Nobel laureate and environmental activist Wangari Maathai:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&#8220;In a few decades, the relationship between the environment, resources and conflict may seem almost as obvious with the relationship we see today between human rights, democracy and peace&#8221; <cite>Wangari Maathai</cite></p>
</blockquote>
<h2>What Does “Tree” Mean to You?</h2>
<p>We would really like to hear from you. Leave a comment below.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	

		<wfw:commentRss>/2015/02/15/what-does-tree-mean-to-you/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>

                            <media:content
                xmlns:media="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                url="http://kijani.co/imagerenderer/img.php?imgurl=http%3A%2F%2Fblog.kijani.ngo%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2015%2F02%2F2015-02-15-What-does-%E2%80%9CTree%E2%80%9D-mean-to-you.jpg&amp;title=What+does+%E2%80%9CTree%E2%80%9D+mean+to+you%3F&amp;width=600&amp;type=jpg&amp;qual=80"
              type="image/jpg"
              medium="image"
              height="337.5"
              width="600"
            />

	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">263</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
