<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Kijani BlogKijani Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Kijani</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 08:39:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.18</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">81697008</site>	<item>
		<title>The Simple Act of a Handshake</title>
		<link>/2018/06/13/the-simple-act-of-a-handshake/</link>
		<comments>/2018/06/13/the-simple-act-of-a-handshake/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 08:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Haron Mambe]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.kijani.co/?p=704</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We applaud the effort of Kenyan leaders taking a stand for reconciliation and against tribalism and corruption.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two things that can be said to be ailing Kenya as a nation, it wouldn’t be wrong to point to the political dissention in the country caused by deep rooted tribalism and the mass plague of corruption clawing away at the spine of Kenya’s stability.</p>
<p>Elections in Kenya have always provided a backdrop to display the ugly face of tribalism that exists. The recent elections on the 8th of August, 2017 was no different in saving the political face of this nation. This was an election marred with conspiracy from the moment the gears were set in motion.</p>
<p>The nation’s citizens were dancing to the tune of high confidence and expecting a shift from the negative norm to a brighter, democratic, free and fair election. This proved not to be the case, as the electoral body charged with safeguarding this mandate, suffered many challenges cascading to the murder of its ICT custodian leading to a compromise of the electronic system that would tally the results, in house divisions among the IEBC officials and threats from the political elites that shook the country’s justice system.</p>
<p>This saw the unwavering stance taken by the political divide both in government and in opposition. In the nation, there existed an eerie calm among its citizens with life on the outside seemingly back to normal. It wasn’t known if this would change any time soon until the unexpected happened on the 9th of March, 2018; President Uhuru Kenyatta and ODM leader Raila Odinga met at Harambee house, emerged to give a press address that was sealed with “The Simple Act of a Handshake”. And just like that, the political stalemate was broken, the eerie calm replaced by genuine calm and the nation rescued from implosion.</p>
<p>Corruption though, seems to have played a blind eye to this gesture by the President and the Opposition leader. The recent spade of scandals to the tune of billions of shillings exposed in the media and public outcry at an all time high have now seen the government take a tougher stance in the fight against corruption.  To applaud this effort we must, but we still must ask, where was this same zeal in the consecutive years past when other instances were reported?</p>
<p>The country seems to be moving once again in the right direction. With the current wheels of motion set to drive out corruption, Kenya is at a crossroads of sorts wherein movement in the right direction will guarantee a better and brighter future ahead. The hope is that this fight will extend into all avenues not leaving behind the forestry sector, to restore the country’s environmental pride and place tougher regulations that will once and for all secure and restore the country’s forestry landscape.</p>
<p>“The Simple Act of a Handshake” that has set the tone in the country, has no option but to keep moving this nation forward into non-discriminatory and progressive development in all counties. This momentum can be channeled towards ensuring good practices in the conservation set up and in institutions such as the Kenya Forestry Service, the Ministry of Environment which would develop great work tempo ensuring good political will for conservation efforts in Kenya.</p>
<p>As Kijani, we take our place and applaud this effort trending in the country zealously looking forward to better days ahead.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	

		<wfw:commentRss>/2018/06/13/the-simple-act-of-a-handshake/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>

                            <media:content
                xmlns:media="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                url="http://kijani.co/imagerenderer/img.php?imgurl=http%3A%2F%2Fblog.kijani.ngo%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2018%2F06%2Fuhuru-raila.jpg&amp;title=The+Simple+Act+of+a+Handshake&amp;width=600&amp;type=jpg&amp;qual=80"
              type="image/jpg"
              medium="image"
              height="337.5"
              width="600"
            />

	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">704</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Miyawaki Reforestation Method</title>
		<link>/2017/09/30/the-miyawaki-method/</link>
		<comments>/2017/09/30/the-miyawaki-method/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 21:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Claire Nasike]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.kijani.co/?p=678</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Kijani is testing the innovative Miyawaki forstation as a model for sustainable income generation.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kijani Forests for Change has been searching for an economic model for sustainable income generation for our forest restoration projects in Marmanet as well as our newly acquired land in Ol Kalau. Currently, we are funded by donors and well-wishers, and realize that in order to become financially sustainable as an organization, we need to tie our value proposition as an organization to market needs.</p>
<p>Many residents in urban areas value greenery and trees in their home spaces or compounds. At the same time, trees take a long time to grow, especially indigenous trees, which take upwards of 20 years to achieve maturity. It is for this reason, that we have been involved in training our staff on setting up demonstration plots for the Miyawaki Method. In partnership with Eshel Garden guesthouse, we have set up two Miyawaki demonstration plots in Karen, Nairobi with a third one underway.</p>
<p>The Miyawaki Method is an ideal economic model for raising the needed funds to propel Kijani’s forest restoration work further. A concept initiated by Dr. Akira Miyawaki, it is aimed at restoring and creating an indigenous forest within 10 years. You can find an excellent article on the method by TED Talks <a href="https://fellowsblog.ted.com/how-to-grow-a-forest-really-really-fast-d27df202ba09">here</a>. In practice, the soil is amended for optimal growth outcomes, seedlings are spaced very close together to induce competition and mulch is used to conserve soil moisture and suppress weed growth.</p>
<p>The Miyawaki Method relies on the following principles for faster growth of trees.</p>
<h2>Indigenous trees</h2>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/image003-564x423.jpg" alt="Various indigenous trees species on Demo Miyawaki Plot." /></p>
<p>Certain trees are better suited for unique ecological environments than others. To have the highest chance of success in terms of tree health and survival, one needs to know the indigenous trees in the proposed rehabilitation area and also select young indigenous seedlings that are under 1 year old. Kijani conducted an inventory assessment of the indigenous trees in the area. We then approached a local Non-Governmental Organization, A-Rocha Kenya, that sells indigenous trees unique to this area, and purchased 984 indigenous trees with 14 different species.</p>
<h2>Land preparation</h2>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/image005-564x423.jpg" alt="Kijani Staff working on the third Demo plot for establishing a Miyawaki Plot." /></p>
<p>For the trees to grow healthy and strong, they need the right nourishment. Land has to be prepared adequately. Land preparation entails mixing manure and rice husks to the soil in equal portions. The manure provides nourishment of vital nutrients, while the perforated husks help water to pass through the soil. In the two demonstration plots, we dug the forestation zones 1 meter deep and added the correct mixture of perforated material (rice and coffee husks), animal manure, and soil before planting the trees. To make sure we prepared the land adequately, Erick, our Forestation Manager, attended a training through <a href="http://www.afforestt.com/">Afforest</a>, an organization promoting the Miyawaki Method in India, to learn about the soil requirements for success of the method.</p>
<h2>Species Competition and Mixing</h2>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/image007-564x423.jpg" alt="Claire Nasike, one of the Kijani Volunteers, checking on the Demo plot." /></p>
<p>In a natural forest, there is intense competition for sunlight. In order for an indigenous forest to grow back in under 10 years, the spacing and placement of trees needs to be carefully considered for maximum growth. Within each square meter, 3 tree seedlings are planted. Because of the good amount of mulch used, weeding is not needed, as the weeds are then suppressed by the mulch. Mixing the species reinforces species diversity and resistance leading to the co-existence of trees.</p>
<h2>Water Conservation</h2>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/image009-564x423.jpg" alt="Water Sprinkler, for watering Miyawaki plot." /></p>
<p>A significant amount of water loss happens through evaporation from the soil surface. By mulching the ground of the area to be rehabilitated, water is preserved. In addition to this, the trees need to be intensely watered, with up to 5 litres per square meter once a week.</p>
<p>We are excited to see the growth of this forest in the coming years and so is Eshel Guesthouse.</p>
<p>In years to come, we see ourselves creating a business service model similar to that of Afforest, offering urban clients – both residential and commercial &#8211; with a service that allows them to establish a forest in small spaces according to their specific wants and needs of the client. Watch this space!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	

		<wfw:commentRss>/2017/09/30/the-miyawaki-method/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>

                            <media:content
                xmlns:media="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                url="http://kijani.co/imagerenderer/img.php?imgurl=http%3A%2F%2Fblog.kijani.ngo%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2017%2F09%2Fimage001-1-e1506855311443-1600x900.jpg&amp;title=The+Miyawaki+Reforestation+Method&amp;width=600&amp;type=jpg&amp;qual=80"
              type="image/jpg"
              medium="image"
              height="337.5"
              width="600"
            />

	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">678</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Even Though it’s Dry, the Plants Are Green</title>
		<link>/2017/04/23/even-though-its-dry-the-plants-are-green/</link>
		<comments>/2017/04/23/even-though-its-dry-the-plants-are-green/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 13:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Oyaga]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.kijani.co/?p=665</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The story of our second follow up trip to Marmanet, to meet the farmers that we trained in conservation agriculture]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It’s Friday around 10:00 am, and I’m moving around from one homestead to the other using a motorbike. The roads greet me with dust being blown towards my face by the strong dry winds emanating from Kaichakun hills just above the Marmanet forest. On my way towards these homesteads I am greeted with both men and women who have seen me in this community. I hesitate to respond to their smile and greeting as the strong winds are blowing dust whenever I open my mouth to respond. Oh maybe this is what we call adventure in the community. These words of Wangari Maathai, who was a daughter to a landless peasant farmer and rose to become the winner of the Nobel Peace Prize in 2004, run in my mind:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>One of the reasons why we started to work with these ordinary peasant farmers so as to educate them that, despite the fact that they are poor, it is in their interest to protect the soil that they have, to protect the forest they have, to protect the land that they have, because if they don&#8217;t do it, things can be only worse tomorrow for them for them and for their children. <cite>Wangari Maathai</cite></p>
</blockquote>
<p>We are making a second follow up trip in Marmanet to meet farmers we had trained in conservation agriculture. We are in the community to meet about twenty five farmers who Kijani had trained in past couple of weeks.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/image001-564x317.png" alt="The green effect of conservation farming despite the dry season" /></p>
<p>As I am meeting these farmers, they welcome me with smiles. I sit either under a tree or under the shadow of their houses created by the sun. As it brightly shines, you might think it decided to have a close fellowship with humans in Marmanet. These farmers narrate with joy the impacts they have seen and experienced after the training they got from Kijani. Full of confidence Dorice recollects her memories; “after the training I prepared a plot where I could practice conservation agriculture. I made compost out of my domestic animals waste I have here in the homestead, I later planted spinach. I made liquid fertilizer from the local plants. My spinach plants are very green because they have mulch and they will be ready in the next two weeks.” I could see gleefulness in her heart through her ageing face and mouth. She smiles gently as she is distracted by one of her cute dogs called Habari (meaning “news”) chasing her small chicken. We all stand up to the rescue of the small, black and white polka dotted chicken running away from the dog now turned to “Habari Mbaya” or “bad news”. We both break out laughing at the extent animals can run whenever they could sense death.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/image003-564x317.png" alt="The joy when you capture the attention of community members" /></p>
<p>Dorice continues with her story, “I can tell you for sure ‘kijana wangu’ (respectable swahili phrase meaning ‘my son’) this method of farming has alleviated my workload in the farm. I only water my spinach once or twice a week. Also I don’t use chemical pesticide and they look more green and healthy than other plots I have used conventional chemicals. Weeding is not part of my plan now as the mulch has taken care of it. I’m amazed by the training Kijani gave me.” The story of this mama gave me hope to continue working with rural communities. She finishes her story by telling me her plans of selling these spinach to act as an income generating channel for the family.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/image005-564x317.png" alt="The happy moments when you harvest the first fruits " /></p>
<p>She then says something that pricks and revitalizes my heart; “even though it’s dry, the plants are green.” This is the true meaning of conservation agriculture. This is a message of hope in the face of the uncertainty of the prevailing weather condition. This message was not only a source of inspiration to her, but it was also to Kijani as an organization. As we are embarking on training smallholder farmers who have little to show, we are applying conservation agriculture as a way of transforming and revitalizing the lives of local rural people in Kenya.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	

		<wfw:commentRss>/2017/04/23/even-though-its-dry-the-plants-are-green/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>

                            <media:content
                xmlns:media="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                url="http://kijani.co/imagerenderer/img.php?imgurl=http%3A%2F%2Fblog.kijani.ngo%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2017%2F04%2Fimage001.png&amp;title=Even+Though+it%E2%80%99s+Dry%2C+the+Plants+Are+Green&amp;width=600&amp;type=jpg&amp;qual=80"
              type="image/jpg"
              medium="image"
              height="337.5"
              width="600"
            />

	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">665</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Embracing New Approaches to Landscape Restoration</title>
		<link>/2017/02/26/embracing-new-approaches-to-landscape-restoration/</link>
		<comments>/2017/02/26/embracing-new-approaches-to-landscape-restoration/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 17:41:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Oyaga]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.kijani.co/?p=657</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Read about our latest training workshop with local farmers in Marmanet]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was travelling to Nyahururu town in Laikipia county, and on my way I was enjoying the beautiful scenic features of my beloved county while trying to digest an interesting phenomenon. Namely, I was pondering how organizations will sometimes adjust their approach or tactics towards achieving their objectives in a flexible manner, but will remain militantly committed to their vision. I looked at our driver and thought of times when other matatu drivers have used different routes yet eventually each one of them arrived at the same destination. These matatu drivers will over speed, overtake and even take short cuts with little restraint but the final goal remains fixed. This, I thought, is an apt representation of the life of a start-up organization.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/image007-564x317.jpg" alt="group photo before the workshop started" /></p>
<p>This time round I was going to Nyahururu not to plant trees in the forest, nor to have an interview with the locals or local administration but rather to mobilize, organize and train farmers on conservation farming techniques. Kijani had identified a need; landscape restoration strategies that are implemented without integrating livelihood improvement components in the methodology are bound to lack buy-in from the community. These projects support a worthy environmental ideal, but are likely to face countless challenges including the potential for total failure. For sustainable landscape restoration to occur, community members need to be on board, and for this to happen tangible economic benefits need to be secured in the model. This day we were training farmers on conservation farming as model for sustainable livelihood improvement and engaging them in tree planting activities. The vegetables grown using the conservation farming techniques enable community members to reap immediate profits from market sale of their produce, providing a means of family sustenance while the trees grow and become economically viable. I arrived in Kwanjiku (the local town center) around midday, engaged farmers and informed them of our training the following day.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/image001-564x317.jpg" alt="Showing practical session in demo plot" /></p>
<p>The training began with our facilitators taking the farmers through the theory behind conservation farming. This part of the training was an eye opener for participants, as they realized that it is possible for any farmer to implement the techniques with little outside input or expensive materials. For example, compost can be created from animal and plant organic matter, and the no-till methodology simply requires a shift in traditional farm practice. The training focused on timely farmland preparation, mulching, making of pesticides using locally available material, how to make compost manure from leaves of tree and lastly how to plant trees and integrate them in agroforestry systems. These farmers were later trained practically on how to carry out these activities in a demonstration plot, then organized into groups to make them mutually responsible to implement the methods on their own farms.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/image003-564x317.jpg" alt="Facilitator showing how to compost manure" /></p>
<p>Amazingly we realized all farmers wanted to plant trees, not because they were told to do so or due to climate change and degradation of forests, but because they were shown how they could reap immediate benefits from conservation farming while at the same waiting for a long term benefits of trees. I would never have crossed my mind before that training community members about conservation farming could be related to agroforestry. Just like the matatu driver who takes a different route to reach his destination, so as Kijani we are continuously evolving in our knowledge of the most effective means to restore landscapes in a sustainable way.<br />
Two things have been confirmed to me; livelihood improvement is pivotal to success, and community members will plant trees on their land if it is complemented by a more immediate means to improve their livelihoods. Motivating farmers to plant trees through training on conservation has proven to be a concept which can be embraced. By taking this approach one will see a change of mindset which will later transform to paradigm shift; a community which will embrace tree planting not as a one-off activity but as a way of life.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/image005-564x372.jpg" alt="facilitator demonstrating how to make liquid organic pesticide" /></p>
<p>Although we changed our tactics we are still stubborn with our vision of landscape restoration through tree planting.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	

		<wfw:commentRss>/2017/02/26/embracing-new-approaches-to-landscape-restoration/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>

                            <media:content
                xmlns:media="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                url="http://kijani.co/imagerenderer/img.php?imgurl=http%3A%2F%2Fblog.kijani.ngo%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2017%2F02%2Fimage001.jpg&amp;title=Embracing+New+Approaches+to+Landscape+Restoration&amp;width=600&amp;type=jpg&amp;qual=80"
              type="image/jpg"
              medium="image"
              height="337.5"
              width="600"
            />

	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">657</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Africa Rising to Forest Landscape Restoration</title>
		<link>/2016/11/17/africa-rising-to-forest-landscape-restoration/</link>
		<comments>/2016/11/17/africa-rising-to-forest-landscape-restoration/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 15:27:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Erick Ogallo]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.kijani.co/?p=648</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Read about Kijani's Participation in the First African Forest Landscape Restoration Initiative (AFR100) Meeting.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One year ago African countries gathered in Durban, South Africa for the XIV World Forestry Congress (WFC). This was the first time this significant conference was taking place on African soil. Looking back on how successful the conference was I can confidently say that this was a major motivation for Africa to champion a restoration agenda and implement strategies on sustainable landscape restoration. I first came to learn about AFR 100 (the African Forest Landscape Restoration Initiative; a country-led effort to bring 100 million hectares of land in Africa into restoration by 2030) when I attended the XIV World Forestry Congress representing Kijani Forests for Change as a youth speaker on forest landscape restoration. You can read all about that, <a href="/blog/2015/10/06/a-young-voice-at-the-world-forest-congress-2015/">here</a>.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/image001-564x317.jpg" alt="Kijani Brochure displayed at the AFR 100 Conference" /></p>
<p>AFR 100 has since made great efforts in mobilizing African countries to share in the agenda of forest landscape restoration of 100 million hectares by 2030. Kenya has committed to restore 5.1 million ha of degraded forest land. This has been followed by a series of consultation meetings to develop restoration options for the degraded landscapes. In addition, stakeholders participated in a regional consultation workshop that took place in Addis Ababa from 12th to 14th of October.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/image003-564x423.jpg" alt="Mr.Peter Ndunda (WRI Kenya) making a presentation during the AFR regional conference" /></p>
<p>The regional workshop provided a platform for the African countries, donors, partner organizations and supporters to brainstorm on some of the pertinent issues that may hinder achievement of restoring 100 million ha by 2030.</p>
<p>As a young conservationist, being part of this initiative and representing my organization Kijani Forests for Change was a great privilege. I was able to learn, share our experience as an upcoming organization in forest conservation and exchange ideas with other participants. We studied successful case studies that have shown the possibilities of undertaking sustainable forest restoration. Participating in this regional workshop gave me hope for the future of African forests. Surrounded by a wealth of knowledge and experiences from other African countries like Niger, Congo, Senegal, Ethiopia, among others I felt relieved that something is being done, and strategies are being developed, to save our African forests.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/image005-564x423.jpg" alt="Erick Ogallo representing Kijani Forests for change during the AFR 100 Conference discussions" /></p>
<p>I was given hope that when upcoming generations ask what effort we made to save our forests, at least I will be able to say with confidence that my generation recognized the gravity of the challenges and came together to fight for sustainable solutions. Only time will tell what our impact with be. AFR 100 is definitely working towards addressing these tough questions. On the other hand, as I interacted with other stakeholders I came to realize that this was not an easy task and it required the efforts of all of us – you and me included! It requires persistent collaboration and constant commitment by African citizens, donors and other stakeholders. Moreover, success relies on political goodwill through favorable policies towards initiatives such as AFR 100. The allocation of valuable resources, and making forest landscape restoration a priority among African heads of state will go a long way to giving these efforts real traction.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/image007-564x423.jpg" alt="“A warm welcome to the AFR 100 conference “ says Sean Dewitt (Director, Global Restoration Initiative)" /></p>
<p>In this journey the youth are not left behind, as there is strong conviction that the sustainability of AFR 100 lies in their adoption of this initiative. Youth should drive this agenda to their peers to get actively engaged in forest landscape restoration for livelihoods establishment and employment creation. We at Kijani Forests for change strongly believe that young people have the capacity to build innovations that can propel sustainable economic empowerment by linking the challenge of climate change with socio-economic opportunities for communities in Africa.</p>
<p>Just as the late Wangari Maathai said, “we are called to assist the Earth to heal her wounds and in the process heal our own – indeed, to embrace the whole creation in all its diversity, beauty and wonder.” This will happen if we see the need to revive our sense of belonging to a larger family of life, with which we have shared our evolutionary process. Let’s all embrace the forest landscape restoration agenda for the sustainability of our African forests. The time is now!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	

		<wfw:commentRss>/2016/11/17/africa-rising-to-forest-landscape-restoration/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>

                            <media:content
                xmlns:media="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                url="http://kijani.co/imagerenderer/img.php?imgurl=http%3A%2F%2Fblog.kijani.ngo%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2016%2F11%2Fimage001.jpg&amp;title=Africa+Rising+to+Forest+Landscape+Restoration&amp;width=600&amp;type=jpg&amp;qual=80"
              type="image/jpg"
              medium="image"
              height="337.5"
              width="600"
            />

	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">648</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kijani Volunteering Experience, Part 2</title>
		<link>/2016/09/07/kijani-volunteering-experience-part-2/</link>
		<comments>/2016/09/07/kijani-volunteering-experience-part-2/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 14:42:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Grace Mercy]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.kijani.co/?p=635</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Read about the experience of our last German and Kenyan volunteers, Johanna and Grace.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Laughter, happiness, and love are what I can recollect about Kijani, 3 months down the memory lane and it feels like yesterday, it’s funny how time really flies. My first time locating the office wasn’t easy, not because it was far but the leafy suburb of Karen environment is not something I am used to. No pun intended by the way .All the corners of the road looked the same to me. The lush green and quite environs of Kijani’s office is a site and feeling to behold .A small safe haven away from the hustle and bustle of the city and matatus and all that drama that comes with it.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/image005-564x423.jpg" alt="“Guys what do you think about this,” David chairs a brainstorming session." /></p>
<p>There’s something unique when young people work together. Crazy, funny and hardworking are the three magic words I can use to describe my co-workers. Beating deadlines for grants and research proposals was the order of the day but a couple of times we could afford to sit down over a cup of tea and have a good laugh.</p>
<p>A quirky medium sized room on your right from the main entrance of the office hosts these two funny guys, David and Erick. David is this kind of guy the moment he’s at the gate you will know he’s around. He’s got this humongous voice and very tall as well (the NBA height) and he’s really passionate about community development. Erick on the other hand is this quite chilled out guy passionate and very knowledgeable about forestry .One of the most sensible people in the office, on the other hand the moment he decides to speak everyone bursts into laughter. He’s a comedian by birth, that’s all I can say.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/image007-564x423.jpg" alt="A learning session about conservation agriculture at A Rocha Kenya" /></p>
<p>Then there’s Johanna, a volunteer from Germany, apart from me, no one at the office gets her second name right. David calls her Cookies while Erick calls her Coocoo! Jeez! (Shaking my head). She’s the kind of lady who keeps everyone on toes especially when writing and submitting grants by making sure we work within the time frame assigned. With her around we don’t need a spelling and grammar icon in our laptops. Very careful on typos and sentence structures.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/image009-1-564x423.jpg" alt="David the funny Guy who makes everyone happy at all time " /></p>
<p>And not forgetting myself, working on budgets and work plans. The 3 months volunteering in Kijani has been a blessing in disguise .The skills I have gained in writing grant proposals, reports and blogs and building friendships and networks is something that no one can take away from me. For the young people out there interested in volunteering on environmental conservation, Kijani is the place to be.</p>
<p>Mercy Grace Amboka — Kenyan Volunteer</p>
<p>Read Part 1 about Johanna&#8217;s experience <a href="/blog/2016/09/07/kijani-volunteering-experience-part-2/">here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	

		<wfw:commentRss>/2016/09/07/kijani-volunteering-experience-part-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>

                            <media:content
                xmlns:media="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                url="http://kijani.co/imagerenderer/img.php?imgurl=http%3A%2F%2Fblog.kijani.ngo%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2016%2F09%2Fimage001-2.jpg&amp;title=Kijani+Volunteering+Experience%2C+Part+2&amp;width=600&amp;type=jpg&amp;qual=80"
              type="image/jpg"
              medium="image"
              height="337.5"
              width="600"
            />

	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">635</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kijani Volunteering Experience, Part 1</title>
		<link>/2016/09/06/kijani-volunteering-experience-part-1/</link>
		<comments>/2016/09/06/kijani-volunteering-experience-part-1/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 19:31:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Johanna Kückes]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.kijani.co/?p=628</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Read about the experience of our last German and Kenyan volunteers, Johanna and Grace.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>About one year ago I was looking for an opportunity to volunteer with an organization involved in reforestation, agroforestry and sustainable forest management in between my Bachelor’s and Master’s Studies. I found Kijani online, met up with Tobias (one of the cofounders) and was deeply impressed by the work Kijani had been doing throughout the past years. Particularly had I been excited about the ideas Kijani had come up with, combining environmental restoration with youth empowerment and the economic development of rural Kenya. These approaches seemed to be equally innovative and holistic, so I happily accepted the offer to work with the motivated Kijani team for three months.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/image001-564x423.jpg" alt="Kijani staff /Volunteers, David far left, Erick, Johanna, Victor and grace Amboka" /></p>
<p>Arriving in Kenya was very easy, thanks to David and Erick (Kijani community engagement and forestation officers) who both warmly welcomed me in the Kijani family. They took me to Marmanet at the end of my first week in Kenya, and made this trip an unforgettable event by taking me on my first motorbike ride and teaching me how to brush my teeth with a tree branch and to peel sugar cane with my teeth. My fellow volunteer, Grace, has not only become a very dear friend but also my Kenyan sister. She took me around Nairobi, enabling me to explore places that I would never had found on my own, taught me how to cook Kenyan food and introduced me to her friends and family. Grace’s family treated me as if I was their own child whenever I visited them. They invited me to various family events in Nairobi and rural Kakamega, allowing me to immerse as deeply in Kenyan cultures and lifestyles as possible within a few months. Even in the Kijani office I could embrace life in Kenya by learning how to cook Ugali (maize porridge) and Skuma Wiki (kale) during lunch breaks.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/image003-564x317.jpg" alt="Happy moments are captured shared the Dog not left out" /></p>
<p>Working with Kijani has been very valuable to me since I could see and participate in the whole process of developing project ideas, applying for grants, implementing projects, following up with community members and evaluating the projects. I particularly enjoyed brainstorming on project ideas and discussing them with my colleagues because every team member is taken seriously and given equal opportunity to bring fourth his or her own ideology Consequently, everyone can contribute with his or her expertise, leading to an environment of mutual learning and growing. Kijani gave me the space to develop and confirmed me in the desire to focus my continuing studies on tropical forestry and sustainable forest management. I c highly recommend anyone to come and volunteer with the Kijani team. You will not regret it!</p>
<p>Johanna Kukces — Volunteer from Germany</p>
<p>Read Part 2 about Grace&#8217;s experience <a href="/blog/2016/09/06/kijani-volunteering-experience-part-1/">here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	

		<wfw:commentRss>/2016/09/06/kijani-volunteering-experience-part-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>

                            <media:content
                xmlns:media="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                url="http://kijani.co/imagerenderer/img.php?imgurl=http%3A%2F%2Fblog.kijani.ngo%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2016%2F09%2Fimage001-2.jpg&amp;title=Kijani+Volunteering+Experience%2C+Part+1&amp;width=600&amp;type=jpg&amp;qual=80"
              type="image/jpg"
              medium="image"
              height="337.5"
              width="600"
            />

	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">628</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sustainable Development Goals and Kijani</title>
		<link>/2016/08/13/sustainable-development-goals-and-kijani/</link>
		<comments>/2016/08/13/sustainable-development-goals-and-kijani/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2016 16:08:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Grace Mercy]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.kijani.co/?p=609</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A look at how Kijani's work relates to the 2030 sustainable development goals]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In September 2015 Heads of State and Government agreed to set the world on a path towards sustainable development through the adoption of the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development. This agenda includes 17 Sustainable Development Goals, or SDGs, which set out quantitative objectives across the social, economic, and environmental dimensions of sustainable development all to be achieved by 2030. From the Millennium Development goals which expired last year in December, never before have had world leaders pledged common action and endeavor across such a broad and universal policy agenda, and this is a step towards the right direction.</p>
<p>Kijani shares a common global vision as the SDGs for a safer environment as well as a sustainable space for all human beings to thrive on this beautiful planet earth. Two years down the line since our existence and we are still committed to the transformational changes in achieving our vision of an environmentally and economically sustainable future focusing on Zero Hunger Climate Action, Life on land and Partnerships for the goals</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/sdgs-564x291.png" alt="The 17 Sustainable Development Goals of the UN" /></p>
<p>Our work in forest restoration in the North Marmanet forest has been quite an experience worth sharing. Commercial harvesting of the forest resources, poverty and population growth in North Marmanet has resulted in detrimental effects on the natural environment as growing numbers of people need more land to cultivate, grass for livestock to graze, and firewood to cook on thus resulting to forest obliteration.</p>
<p>For the past six months, Kijani has been working with farmers in sustainable agriculture with special attention in agroforestry and conservation agricultural techniques. This has been made possible through workshops and field demonstrations. Through this type of farming, households will be able to increase their crop yields as well as diversify their crops reducing instances of malnutrition and other poor diet related disease contributing to Zero Hunger. Furthermore, Kijani is empowering the youth to engage in conservation agriculture by equipping them with theoretical and practical skills. Hence, unemployment levels and poverty levels are reduced.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/image003-564x344.jpg" alt="Kijani members learning about conservation agriculture " /></p>
<p>The climate is changing. Perhaps this might be breaking news to some of you, but if you have been keen then this is not news. The average temperatures are rising and extreme weather events – particularly floods and droughts causing havoc become more frequent. Deforestation is just one of the influencers of climate change and the once green North Marmanet forest has suffered this cataclysm. Kijani has been on the forefront working with the local communities and the Community Forest Association in rehabilitation of North Marmanet forest. So in case you wondering why Kijani is pro tree planting, let me take you through a biology class for a minute. Trees and forests act as carbon sinks. When growing, trees absorb carbon from the atmosphere through photosynthesis and store the carbon in the form of wood. This reduces the amount of carbon in the atmosphere Trees and forests can contribute to combating climate if they are well managed both locally and globally. Kenyan farmers are driving pollinators and other soil living organisms into extinction threating food security and sustainability. This has been attributed to the fact that farmers are using unscrupulous farming techniques and chemicals posing a negative effect to these organisms. About 80% of the food crops depend on pollination by insects and other organisms. Unfortunately the rate at which we are losing our biodiversity might present a challenge in a few years to come. Kijani has been promoting conservation agriculture with farmers in North Marmanet. This form of agricultural practice promotes minimal or no tillage. Hence, the disturbance of the soil biodiversity, such as worms and other microorganisms, is reduced to a minimum. The use of compost manure and biological pest control is highly endorsed hence protecting pollinators, such as bees and butterflies, from extinction and decline in number.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/image005-1-564x340.jpg" alt="SDGs assures the future of Ecosystem Diversity " /></p>
<p>Many ecosystem challenges cross-jurisdictional boundaries. Thus, systematic changes beyond the capabilities of an individual organization or company are required. In this case, partnerships with governments, local communities, non-governmental organizations, investors and companies are the most crucial ones. As Kijani we believe in the old adage that alone we can do little; but together we can do much. Throughout our past and current projects, we have created strong collaborations with both international, government and private institutions such as Kenya Forest Service, Dove International, Plant for the Planet Movement mentioning but a few. Some of our volunteers have had the opportunity to attend international meetings on Forestry and climate change in South Africa and Germany expanding Kijani’s networks. Currently we are hosting an intern from Germany and we looking forward to providing opportunities and hands on experience for other young people all over the world. These partnerships have been useful in bolstering our reputation and operation in achieving our vision. Kijani is determined to protect the planet from degradation through sustainably managing its natural resources and taking urgent action on climate change in order to support the needs of the present and future generations.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	

		<wfw:commentRss>/2016/08/13/sustainable-development-goals-and-kijani/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>

                            <media:content
                xmlns:media="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                url="http://kijani.co/imagerenderer/img.php?imgurl=http%3A%2F%2Fblog.kijani.ngo%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2016%2F08%2Fworldpeople1200x7171-copy.jpg&amp;title=Sustainable+Development+Goals+and+Kijani&amp;width=600&amp;type=jpg&amp;qual=80"
              type="image/jpg"
              medium="image"
              height="337.5"
              width="600"
            />

	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">609</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Warm Welcome in Kenya</title>
		<link>/2016/07/07/a-warm-welcome-in-kenya/</link>
		<comments>/2016/07/07/a-warm-welcome-in-kenya/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 17:40:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Johanna Kückes]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.kijani.co/?p=595</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[An account of the first few weeks  in Kenya of our new German intern Johanna, meeting the team and visiting farmers in Marmanet]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>About a month ago, on June 1st, I arrived in Nairobi. It was Madaraka Day. “Madaraka” means “Power” in Kiswahili and marks the day when Kenya attained internal self-rule in 1963. Since it is a public holiday, the streets were — by Nairobi’s standards — empty and I reached Karen area, where the Kijani office is located, within only a few minutes. The next day I had the pleasure to meet David and Erick, both active members of the Kijani team, who greeted me very warm-heartedly and were eager to teach me some basic words and phrases in Kiswahili. Soon we started planning our trip to North Marmanet the next week in order to follow-up with the farmers who had participated in Kijani’s preceding conservation agriculture workshop.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/image001-564x381.jpg" alt="Johanna, David, and Erick in Nairobi" /></p>
<p>On June 9th, after a 4-hour matatu drive — minibuses making up the main share of public transportation in Kenya — from Nairobi to Nyahururu, Erick, David and I headed to North Marmanet in order to visit the tree nursery that had been established for our reforestation projects. Since the nursery was very remote, we had to take a second matatu and a motorcycle which they call “Pikipiki”. On the way I noticed huge patches of deforested land. Most of them were used for agriculture, particularly for the cultivation of maize, others functioned as grazing grounds for cattle, sheep, and goats. Knowing that this area had been almost completely covered with forests just a few decades ago strengthened my conviction that reforestation is most likely only successful and sustainable in this area when agriculture is included in any sort of restoration and conservation plans. Improved yields through conservation agriculture, for instance, could function as an incentive to also get involved in reforestation activities.</p>
<p>Reaching the village, the local farmer in charge for the nursery welcomed us warm-heartedly and showed us the around 3300 healthy and well-nurtured indigenous tree seedlings he is tending for. He even offered us Guavas and his wife prepared local maize porridge, famously known as “Ugali”, and some delicious fried eggs.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/image003-564x402.jpg" alt="Erick by one of the Kijani tree nurseries with the local care taker" /></p>
<p>This great hospitality continued the next day when we visited farmers who had previously participated in the conservation agriculture workshop. They offered us tea, sugar cane, bananas and avocados making me feel very welcome even though, due to language barriers, I couldn’t directly communicate with community members. Even the children faced me with great curiosity, whispering and sometimes shouting “Mwzungu, mwzungu”, which means “European” or more general “white person”. When I responded with a smile and “Mwafrika, mwafrika” (“African person”), they started laughing and the ice was broken.</p>
<p>I felt that the local farmers were happy to see us as well as highly motivated to continue working with Kijani in the future and participating in upcoming activities. In addition to that, I could observe farmers being passionately involved in discussions with Erick and David, explicitly expressing their experiences and concerns with conservation agriculture. These insights will help us to adopt our current strategy of promoting conservation agriculture techniques in North Marmanet, stressing once more the great importance of the involvement of local communities in the process of developing future strategies. These inspiring conversations also showed that, once given the opportunity, most farmers in North Marmanet have an open mind when it comes to the adaptation and application of new techniques, and are eager to learn about alternative sustainable farming methods.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/image005-564x423.jpg" alt="Erick with a local farmer in a field planted during the conservation agriculture workshop" /></p>
<p>This trip gave me the confidence that the farmers in North Marmanet are keen to get actively involved in further projects and workshops dealing with conservation agriculture and forest restoration. I am looking forward to following up with them during upcoming field visits, and I feel blessed to have the opportunity to be a part of the Kijani team for the next few months.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	

		<wfw:commentRss>/2016/07/07/a-warm-welcome-in-kenya/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>

                            <media:content
                xmlns:media="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                url="http://kijani.co/imagerenderer/img.php?imgurl=http%3A%2F%2Fblog.kijani.ngo%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2016%2F07%2Fimage001.jpg&amp;title=A+Warm+Welcome+in+Kenya&amp;width=600&amp;type=jpg&amp;qual=80"
              type="image/jpg"
              medium="image"
              height="337.5"
              width="600"
            />

	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">595</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Conservation Agriculture for better Livelihoods</title>
		<link>/2016/05/09/an-ideal-method-of-improving-community-livelihood/</link>
		<comments>/2016/05/09/an-ideal-method-of-improving-community-livelihood/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 08:09:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Oyaga]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.kijani.co/?p=573</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Read about Kijani's successful Conservation Agriculture training of Community Members in Central Kenya]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am traveling down to Marmanet on Monday morning. An early arrival at Kwanjiku village will enable me to make prior arrangements for our capacity-building training on conservation agriculture. Reaching Kwanjiku around mid-morning, I start the preparations. As a norm of community change agents, I went straight to the Assistant Chief’s office to report the purpose of my visit. I took the shortest time possible to explain to her that Kijani will be conducting training on conservation agriculture and thirty community members are expected to attend. The mobilization process starts right away as Madam Chief Naomi accepts the idea and directs me to several other assistant chiefs in the location to assist me. With the permission of community gatekeepers, I start to make phones calls, meet people within my network, and meet the local forester. My last stop is talking to the Chairman of Community Forest Association.</p>
<p>By evening, before I get back to my hotel room in Nyahururu town, I am overwhelmed with phone calls from all corners of Kwanjiku. Community members are highly interested as they express their desire to be part of the training, but deep down in my heart I am starting to get worried. The number is going to be above thirty people, but I later consoled my heart by saying, “Better a high number than zero attendance”. I am expecting our trainers, Francis Ogembo and Jesse Kilel, and Eric Ogallo, the moderator, and Piere Bertrand who will be taking the video footage of the training to arrive tomorrow. I am going to sleep with an inflated confidence… the training must succeed.</p>
<p>The following day we all assembled on the grounds of the Presbyterian Church of East Africa (PCEA). Community members came from all corners starting from Kwanjiku, Ngoru, Kaichakun, Gatero and as far as Njefi. All roads leading to the PCEA grounds where the anticipated training is to take place. People of all ages and genders come: men, women, youth, middle age, and old. With the number surpassing the target, our trainers go ahead and start with 40 community members. But confirming my instincts, 30 minutes into the training the venue is fully packed with 65 community members ready to listen, learn, transfer knowledge, and apply skills learned.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/image001-564x317.jpg" alt="Francis Ogembo, one of the Trainers, doing a demonstration on how to plant seeds." /></p>
<p>Day one starts by taking community members through the concepts of conservation agriculture. This takes the centre stage where mulching, crop rotation, manure composting, field or farm preparation, among others, are taught. Our two trainers find it hard to respond to the number of questions coming from over 60 enthusiastic community members. The spirit of learning is really in them and the raising of hands was the only way to show they had burning questions. In the middle of the training one community member shouts to our trainer in Swahili “kwekwe kwekwe kwekwe” meaning “weed weed weed”. We were shocked and thought that we had committed a heinous crime in the training floor, later to realize that he wanted to share his nasty experience of weeds in his farm and he needed much help. People bursted out in laughter. “That was a spice in the training”, one community member commented. Day one ended with a powerful thanksgiving prayer.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/image003-564x317.jpg" alt="Community members getting engaged during the practical training." /></p>
<p>The second and last day of the training is dedicated for the practical work. We all assemble in our church venue and go straight to Mr. Haman’s plot, one of the trainee’s piece of land which he had dedicated for demonstration. Our trainers show community members how to prepare land, minimize soil disturbance, make holes for crops and vegetables, top dressing with animal manure, and the making of compost manure, among others. This is the highly interactive part of our training and our trainees are highly involved and participate in the process. This session makes them realize that low yields are a result of inadequate techniques. It is evident that the most ideal method of improving community livelihood at the household level is through embracing conservation agriculture, which involves learning the skills and correctly applying your knowledge.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/image005-564x423.jpg" alt="David Oyaga from Kijani demonstrating his participatory skills." /></p>
<p>We later climb the hills of Marmanet to reach our second demonstration plot where Mama Wambui offers her portion of land as a demo plot. Although we reach her home when we are tired and exhausted, our trainers go ahead to demonstrate to the remaining group how to plant and prepare land. I will never forget how our Moderator Erick Ogallo had the energy and passion to get videos of testimonials from the few participants who could speak Swahili, while I was kept busy supplying our trainers with mulch from fallen tree leaves and other agricultural wastes, and community members were focused on learning the practical aspect of the training. We later distribute the training manuals to the farmers, which are to act as a guide and reference book for the farmers. This is well received, and the smiles that are written all over their faces could ascertain this.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/image007-564x423.jpg" alt="It was a happy ending for the successful training we had." /></p>
<p>It was a happy ending due to the warm reception we got from the community members, and the support from both community gatekeepers and stakeholders. Kijani being a youthful organization, we were impressed by the turnout of young people who showed interest and further committed their time to attend our training and implement the model. One great pan-African leader once said, &#8220;Communities cannot be developed, they can only develop themselves by participating in development activities.&#8221; This is exactly what we witnessed.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	

		<wfw:commentRss>/2016/05/09/an-ideal-method-of-improving-community-livelihood/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>

                            <media:content
                xmlns:media="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                url="http://kijani.co/imagerenderer/img.php?imgurl=http%3A%2F%2Fblog.kijani.ngo%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2016%2F05%2F2-1600x900.jpg&amp;title=Conservation+Agriculture+for+better+Livelihoods&amp;width=600&amp;type=jpg&amp;qual=80"
              type="image/jpg"
              medium="image"
              height="337.5"
              width="600"
            />

	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">573</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
